Phil Stubbs

 $philipstubbs 13@gmail.com \mid 952\text{-}454\text{-}3933 \mid Burnsville, MN \\ \underline{https://github.com/philipstubbs 13} \mid \underline{https://www.linkedin.com/in/philipjstubbs/} \mid \underline{http://www.philstubbs.com}$

Web developer who is passionate about designing experiences that make people's lives simple.

Project manager who can resolve problems quickly and keep teams moving forward.

Tech enthusiast who loves learning about new tools and technologies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML the command line GitHub CSS MySQL Handlebars Materialize Firebase **Express** Bootstrap Media Queries XMetaL Node.is **APIs Oxygen Javascript** ISON Arbortext **REST**

jQuery REST GIT AJAX

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota2017 – PresentCollege of Continuing and Professional StudiesSt. Paul, MN

Full Stack Web Development Certificate

University of Minnesota

2009 - 2013

College of Liberal Arts

Minneapolis, MN

Bachelor of Science in Scientific and Technical Communication

Emphasis in Information Technology and Design

GPA 3.974; Dean's List: Fall 2009, Spring 2010, Fall 2010, Spring 2011, Fall 2011, Spring 2012, Fall 2012, Spring 2013

APPS BUILT

MyCookingAssistant

2018

Project Manager/Front End Developer

St. Paul, MN

- Developed an app that returns recipes from the most popular sites on the web.
- Created a Trello board to lead a team of 4 developers, build user stories, assign tasks, create a schedule, set priorities, and meet the project deadline.
- Managed the team GitHub repository, which included resolving merge conflicts, managing pull requests, and keeping the master branch production ready.
- Designed the user interface using Materialize, HTML5, CSS, Javascript, and jQuery.
- https://github.com/philipstubbs13/Project-Longshot
- http://www.mycookingassistant.com

LIRI 2018

Back End Developer

St. Paul, MN

• Developed a command line app that allows you to retrieve your latest tweets from Twitter, song information from Spotify, and movie information from OMDB.

- Built using Node.js, Javascript, and NPM packages (Request, Spotify, Twitter, Columnify, and Figlet).
- https://github.com/philipstubbs13/liri-node-app

Star Wars RPG Game 2018

Front End Developer

St. Paul, MN

- Created a Star Wars Role Playing Game (RPG) that can be played in the browser.
- Built using JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS, and Bootstrap.
- https://github.com/philipstubbs13/Star-Wars-RPG-Game
- https://philipstubbs13.github.io/Star-Wars-RPG-Game/

myTrainBuilder 2018

Back End Developer

St. Paul. MN

- Created a train schedule application that incorporates Firebase to host arrival and departure data.
- Built using JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Firebase API, jQuery, and Moment.js.
- https://github.com/philipstubbs13/Firebase-Train-Scheduler
- https://fir-train-scheduler-7f4a9.firebaseapp.com/

WORK EXPERIENCE

Medtronic2017 - PresentTechnical WriterMounds View, MN

Mounds view, M.
 Build and update the online help, user manual, and installation manual for the Paceart Optima System (a patient and device management software application).

- Collaborate with engineering and human factors to create a patient manual for a home remote monitor that receives information from a patient's heart device and relays that information to the patient's doctor.
- Work closely with development and human factors to update the online help for the Reveal LINQ Mobile Manager app (an app used by clinics to interrogate a patient's implanted heart monitor).

Oracle 2014 - 2016

Software Technical Writer

Nashua. NH

- Used DITA and CCMS authoring tools to create and develop documentation that helps users install, configure, and effectively use Oracle software.
- Researched and analyzed information about a new product or feature by interviewing key subject matter experts and working hands-on with the product to quickly learn technical concepts.